## MIKE GROUCHY

613-898-0274 mgrouchy@gmail.com http://mikegrouchy.com

407D Mackay St Ottawa, Ontario K1M2C5

#### **Profile**

Entrepreneurial developer with over 8 years experience and over 5 years specializing in Python and Django development. Fully engaged in developing the entire stack from systems administration tasks to implementing interactions on the front end. Interested in Open Source software and contributing back whenever possible.

#### **Experience**

## Co-Founder/Curator, Pycoders Weekly — Feb. 2012 - Present

Started Pycoders out of a belief that content curation provides value. Grew newsletter to over 15000 subscribers and twitter account to over 6000 followers. The Pycoder's Weekly newsletter and Job Board have had advertising clients such as Uber, Vine, MongoDB Inc., Path, MIT and more.

### Software Developer, Source Metrics - Oct. 2009 - Present

Architected and lead development of a suite of social analytics tools in Python and Django through multiple iterations as the first developer hire at Source Metrics. These tools provided the technical foundation for the company to raise \$1.5M dollars in venture capital.

Developed tools to gather, warehouse and report on data from Social Networks such as Twitter, Facebook, LinkedIn, Youtube, Foursquare and others. Also wrote publishing integrations for Twitter, Facebook and LinkedIn as part of a suite of Social Media Marketing tools. Lead development on multiple projects, both internally and for external clients such as Corel Software and John St.

## Programmer Analyst, HRSDC - Jan. 2009 - Sept. 2009

After successfully completing an internship at HRSDC I was hired on as the sole developer to design an enterprise imaging ingestion and distribution workflow to streamline the work of distributed teams in Service Canada centres across Canada.

#### Intern Programmer, HRSDC - Sept 2007 - Dec. 2009

Completed a 16 month internship working as a C#/<u>VB.Net</u> developer. Lead a team of other students to complete various web/web service projects for internal clients. I designed and developed web applications using <u>VB.NET/C#/ASP.net</u> and Oracle and developed internal SOAP web services using .Net and WSE 3.0.

# Google Summer of Code Student, Wordpress — March 2007 - Aug 2007

Was chosen as one of 850 students worldwide from a pool of over 6500 applicants to participate in the program. I worked on updating the comments panel in the admin UI of the open source blogging platform Wordpress, writing both the backend in PHP and the frontend changes required in Javascript.

Systems Programmer, Memorial University, Department of CS — 2006-2007 Designed and developed web applications in Python CGI/PHP. I wrote and contributed to a suite of tools used for automating lab management (<a href="http://labnet.ca">http://labnet.ca</a>) such as imaging computers and deploying new operating systems configurations for networked Linux, Mac and Windows machines. I also developed scripts as needed to handle general systems administration tasks in Python and Bash in a Linux environment.

#### **Education**

Memorial University, St.John's, Newfoundland, Canada — BSc. 2008

## **Technical Skills**

Proficient with: Python, Javascript, Java ,C#, VB, .NET, PHP, SQL, Django, Flask, HTML, CSS, MySQL, PostgeSQL, Redis, OSX, Linux(Debian/Ubuntu).

#### References

Available Upon Request.